

# VIACHESLAV KYSIL

SENIOR WEB DEVELOPER ● EUROPEAN UNION

## • DETAILS •

European Union <a href="mailto:primazp@icloud.com">primazp@icloud.com</a>

• LINKS •

GitHub

**StackOverflow** 

**LinkedIn** 

• SKILLS •

Ruby

Ruby on Rails

JavaScript

React.js

SQL

PostgreSQL

MySQL

Redis

Git

Nginx

Rspec

Sidekiq

WebSockets

## • LANGUAGES •

English

#### ♣ PROFILE

Web engineer specializing in architecting and developing Ruby on Rails backend APIs and JavaScript driven client-side applications. My expertise extends across the entire development lifecycle – from conceptualization and coding to deployment and ongoing management in production environments.

Let's build something remarkable together!

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

## Senior Web Developer at SpotEasy Inc., Boston, MA

June 2023 — Present

Curretly working as a full stack developer on a brand new approach to make renting easy in the Boston area of USA. Major areas:

- Improved search operations perforance
- Implemented API integrations with Google API and other various services

### Lead developer at Nucleus (ex. Mastermind Manager), Austin, TX

May 2017 — August 2023

I was hired as the very first developer on the project and built MVP from scratch. After a year of work developers team started to grow and I gradually transitioned to being a Lead developer on a project responsible for most important parts of the project development and maintenance, including code review, architecture planning, deployments, linux server maintenance, etc.

# Senior Full-stack developer at Rhino Labs Inc., New York, USA

May 2017 — December 2022

I started to work on a very first version of a project as a senior developer and with the company growth gradually transitioned to being an expert responsible for most crucial parts of the codebase. Together with my team members, we grew Rhino to a multimillion company level.

#### Elixir Developer at Flight School Manager, West Jordan, UT, USA

December 2019 — September 2020

Flight School Manager is a powerful all-in-one tool to manage flight school. I worked as Elixir and PhoenixFramework developer on this project and was responsible for development of web dashboard and API for iOS application.

Major milestones:

- Built an automatic payment system that invoices user using flight data (via Stripe)
- Added schools onboarding flow
- Implemented Document Management System

#### Ruby on Rails consultant at Jurata, Zürich, Switzerland

February 2019 — November 2019

Jurata is the best lawyers database in Switzerland. I was responsible for project maintenance, features and ingerations development. While working on Jurata I

significantly improved customer data flow between Segment.com, Intercom.com and Jurata database.

### Ruby/JavaScript Developer at Flatstack

April 2016 — June 2017

- Ruby and Ruby on Rails developing. Mentoring
- Backend development (high-load, scalability)
- SQL queries analysis and optimization (PostgreSQL)
- Client side development with React and Redux
- Wrote software for acl.com, premiumparking.com and securedgenetworks.com

Together with my teammates won internal hackaton by developing bulk upload feature in less than 24 hrs

## Ruby/JavaScript developer at Racoons Group

February 2015 — April 2016

I transitioned from regular to lead developer of a team responsible for one of the largest company projects: interneturok.ru. Solution stack: Ruby on Rails, AngularJS, CoffeeScript, MySQL, Nginx, Unicorn, Sidekiq/Redis, Rspec, Jasmine.

## Web developer at Freelance

August 2014 — February 2015

Developed front end and back end of JavaPractice online service: java programming problems archive with automatic solution verification system. Technologies used: AngularJS, CoffeeScript, Spring Framework, MySQL, Junit, Jasmine.

## EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, ZNTU

September 2007 — June 2012

## **¶** REFERENCES

References available upon request